

ABOUT ME

Date of Birth: February 4, 1989 Age: 30 Gender: Male Birth Place: Montevideo, Uruguay

CONTACT



Juan Ramon Gomez, 3137 Montevideo, Uruguay



(+598) 94 765 315



gmelgaba@gmail.com

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)
English (Basic professional competence)

GONZALO MELGAR

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER I

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I'm a result-driven software engineer with 6+ years development experience, learning while I work with great people. I consider myself a proactive person, and I really encourage best practices. I think that there are always new things to learn.

EDUCATION

2018 Software Engineer

Completed a 5 years Bachelor's degree. Facultad de Ingenieria, Universidad de la Republica.

2016 Computer Analyst

Completed a 3 years degree. Facultad de Ingenieria, Universidad de la Republica.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web development:

Cross-browser compatibility.

Frontend: HTML, CSS, SASS, MaterializeCSS, , jQuery, AngularJS, Angular 2+.
Backend: ExpressJS, NodeJS, GulpJS, PHP Laravel, PHP Slim, Ruby, Ruby on rails.
Database: MongoDB, Mongoose, DynamoDB, Vogels, and Sequelize.
Testing: Chai, Mocha, Jasmine, Postman, Jest,

Mobile:

Native: Android. Hybrids Frameworks: Ionic, Phonegap/Cordova, Titanium AppCelerator.

Others:

Heroku, Docker, Amazon Web Services (ElasticBeanstalk, EC2, S3, Lambda, Kinesis).

EXPERIENCE

TARMAC - Montevideo, UY

Jun. 2014 to present | Full Stack Developer

Collaborated in a team-focused environment providing software solutions to diverse industry US clients.

- Medaptive Health: a platform that engages participants in their day-to-day lives in order to collect data and transform how clinical trials are operated. (1 year & 10 months)
 - Maintained and added features to existing web portals built using Angular. JS.
- Maintained and added features to an API built in Node.JS, using different technologies like mongoose, ExpressJS, Jest, among others.
 - Built and maintained a web portal using Angular 7, starting the project from scratch.
- Built db scripts that handles migration/sanity check to meet new requirements.
- MyAlerts: built and maintained different features over the years. (3 years & 4 months)
- Maintained and added features to an API built in nodeJŚ. Using different technologies like DynamoSDK, Vogels, GulpJS, ExpressJS, among others. (10 months)
- Built PHP parsers to scrap information about the client websites if they didn't support a custom API for their products. (7 months)
 - Built email templates using HTML with Embedded RuBy. (3 months)
- Built an internal web portal for internal configuration using Angular2 + MaterializeCSS. (3 months)
 - Added small features and Maintained Ruby microservices doing small features. (4 months)
- Built and maintained custom scripts to inject in different portals. Assisted technical meetings with the third party that wanted to acquire this custom scripts, being able to respond the questions about it. (13 months)
- Survey Vitals: built and rewrote many core components of their application in PHP Laravel. I was responsible for the development and testing of many of their core surveys. (12 months)
- **Celiac Care:** built and maintained a mobile application that helps individuals manage their Celiac Disease. This app was built in Ionic which is Angular.JS based. The backend was built in Node.JS, but we had limited exposure. We essentially just worked with the endpoints provided by the Backend Developer. (2 months)
- endpoints provided by the Backend Developer. (2 months)
 Primacare: built and maintained features for a Ruby on Rails app for a group of clinics that are attempting to create a primary care network. This Rails app was also integrated with a CMS for content management purposes. (3 months)
- Hire: built an applicant tracking system in Ruby on Rails with a few other team members

INTERESTS

Videogames

Books

Sports

Music

Boardgames

Coffee

HOBBIES









EXPERIENCE

SPIRIA S.R.L. - Montevideo, UY

Oct. 2011 to Jun. 2014 | Developer

Collaborated in a team-focused environment providing creation, and support in different application, mostly web and mobile hybrids.

- **Biptic:** a website that allowed the user to locate all the products from the local stores, comparing their current prices, offering the user the best option available in the market. Responsible for some feature development, bug fixing, and maintance. (7 months)
- MedFit: built and maintained a mobile application in Phonegap, that helps patients with terminal disease conditions, allowing them to do a follow-up and schedule excercises encouraging the patients to continue their routine. Responsable for most of the application development, screen designs, bug fixing and maintenances. (8 months)
- Taxi Seguro: a mobile application built in Phonegap, that allowed the users to book a taxi, and follow the trip in real time. Responsible for most of the app development, and backend implementation. (8 months)
- Picmure: a mobile application built in AppCelerator Titanium, (3 months)
- AstroPay Card: built and maintained a native Android mobile application from scratch, that is basically a prepaid virtual card, integrated with online websites allowing the user to finish his/her payments with a few simple steps. Responsible for most of the app development, bug fixing and maintenance. (4 months)
- AFAP Sura, El inversionista: a we application to simulate the stock market, investments, and profets of it. Responsible of the frontend implementation. (3 months)

VTV URUGUAY - Montevideo, UY

Mar. 2010 to Oct. 2011 | Graphics Operator

Responsible for producing suitable accurate graphic captions across a variety of live productions and different national events.

- Daily broadcasts: VTV Noticias Morning Edition, Dia a Dia, VTV Noticias Noon Edition, Sin limite.
- Weekly broadcasts/Events: Rumbo a la Cancha, Mid-term elections, South American U-20 Championship, Uruguayan Championship, American Cup 2011, Basketball Matches for the national tournament.

PUBLISHED ARTICLES

Multi Source Spatial Queries in the IDEuy Context- Oct. 2014

Authors: Liber Dovat; Nicolas Furquez; Gonzalo Melgar; Diego Perez.

This article arises from a research project of GIS technologies conducted in the subject "Workshop on Business Geographic Information Systems" given at the Facultad de Ingenieria, Universidad de la Republica.